

Navin Prakash

Key Account Manager



Summary

An industrious professional with more than 6 years of experience in the field of Sales & Marketing. A demonstrated self starter with strong technical, communication and presentation skill. Proven leadership and achievement of results by using my acquired experience and abilities to benefit the organisation and the self.

Now looking forward to a making a significant contribution in a ambitious and exciting company that offers a genuine opportunity for progression.



Experience

08/2018 - present

Key Account Manager

Allergan India Limited.

Job Responsibilities

- Since August 13th, 2018 to till date experience in Allergan in Retina Super Specialty div. for vitreous injection, based at Chennai.
- Maximizing revenue from existing customer through complete scientific data and report.
- Maintaining high levels of product & customer knowledge and participating in training program as appropriate.
- Highly mobile attitude charged me for frequent travel across my assigned territory for better follow up and procedures order.
- Capable of taking responsibility as i am generating business from top cataract surgeons and from top eye hospitals.
- Developing customized territory plans.
- Carrying reputed and blockbuster product Ozurdex(Dexamethasone).

11/2014 -08/2018

Scientific Sales Executive.

Sanofi India Limited.

Job Responsibilities

- Worked under Diabetes Team, promoting innovator product like Amaryl,
 Cetapin, Zemiglo.
- Worked for new era vaccine Fluquadri and given significant contribution.
- Managing good relationship with KOLs and KBLs.
- Handling major key account and top hospitals in Chennai.
- Launched many new product and contribute in making it bigger.
- Monitoring competition and analyzing competitor activity.
- Attending sales conferences and industry marketing events.
- Maintaining high levels of product & customer knowledge and participating in training programmes as appropriate.
- Developing customized territory plans.

08/2012 -10/2014

Business Officer

Bayer Pharmaceutical

Job Responsibilities

- Worked under Diabetes Team, promoting innovator product like Glucobay, Metbay, Xirtam.
- Managing good relationship with KOLs and KBLs.





Address

C/O. G. Mohan, House No.-39, 6Th Street, Janaki Nagar, Maduravoyal, Chennai- 600095, Tamilnadu

Phone

9940176416

E-mail

navin_ask@rediffmail.com

Date of birth

12-02-1990

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/navinprakash12021990



Sales & Marketing Management.



Account & Revenue Management.



Negotiation & Presentation Skills.



Task Prioritization & Time Management.



Issues & Complaints Handling



Analytical & Managerial Skills.



Fine

- Handling major key account and top hospitals in Chennai.
- Identifying and maximizing revenue from existing customer accounts.
- Monitoring competition and analyzing competitor activity.
- Attending sales conferences and industry marketing events.
- Maintaining high levels of product & customer knowledge and participating in training programmes as appropriate.
- Travelling to the homes & offices of potential clients for appointments.
- Developing customized territory plans.

Education

05/2015 -06/2017 Master of Business Administration

MBA from Sikkim Manipal University.

06/2008 -07/2012 Bachelor of Engineering

B.E.Biotechnology from Vinayaka Mission University.

12th from CBSE

Done my 12th from Rose Public School.

• 10th from CBSE

Done my 10th from RPS Public School.

Achievement

- Awarded for Extraordinary Performance for the year 2017-18.
 - Awarded as Business Unit Head for the year 2016.
 - Sales Marathon winner two times in year 2017.
 - Performance Excellence Award for newly launched product in 2016.
 - Product Sales Winner for 2nd quarter in 2017.
 - Consistent winner for new product achievement month after month in 2018.

O Courses and Certification

- Personality Development Workshop and Training at Sanofi India.
- 1 week training of communication skills and soft skills.
- 15 days training in MAHAVIR CANCER RESEARCH INSTITUTE.
- Training in SHRM for 10 days on Recombinant DNA Technology.
- Presented a Poster in the zonal conference on "Recent Trends in Plant Physiologically & Crop Improvement" in VIT.
- Member of Indian Society of Technical Education.

Interests

- Long drive with pillion.
- enjoy teaching.
- Reading and watching suspense and thrill based novel/drama.
- Cooking non veg dishes.

Good Interpersonal Skills.

Advanced

Team Coordination & Suppor.





English

Proficient

Hindi

Proficient

Tamil

Can speak and understand